Yongwei Chen | Curriculum Vitae

 \square +86 155-2122-5171 \diamond \heartsuit Singapore

Computer Vision | 3D Vision | Multimodal Learning | Graphics

OVERVIEW

I am a PhD student in MMLab@NTU, supervised by Prof. Xingang Pan. Prior to this, I earned both my Master's and Bachelor's degrees at South China University of Technology (SCUT), under the mentorship of Prof. Kui Jia. My primary research interest lies in the exciting and constantly-evolving realm of 3D vision and graphics, with a particular emphasis on 3D generation.

EDUCATION

PhD student

College of Computing and Data Science

Supervisor: Prof. Xingang Pan

Master's Degree

Information and Communication Engineering

Supervisor: Prof. Kui Jia

Bachelor's degree

School of Electronic and Information Engineering

GPA: 3.92/4.00, rank 3/242

Nanyang Technological University

2024.08 - present

South China University of Technology

2020.09 - 2023.12

South China University of Technology

2016.09 - 2020.06

RECENT PUBLICATION

- [1] Y. Chen*, T. Wang*, T. Wu, X. Pan, K. Jia and Z. Liu, "ComboVerse: Compositional 3D Assets Creation Using Spatially-Aware Diffusion Guidance.", in European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), 2024.
- [2] R. Chen*, Y. Chen*, N. Jiao and K. Jia, "Fantasia3D: Disentangling Geometry and Appearance for High-quality Text-to-3D Content Creation.", in International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV), 2023.
- [3] Y. Chen, R. Chen, J. Lei, Y. Zhang and K. Jia, "TANGO: Text-driven Photorealistic and Robust 3D Stylization via Lighting Decomposition.", in Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2022. spotlight
- [4] Y. Chen*, Z. Wang*, L. Zou, K. Chen, and K. Jia, "Quasi-Balanced Self-Training on Noise-Aware Synthesis of Object Point Clouds for Closing Domain Gap.", in European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), 2022.
- [5] M. Yang, Y. Wen, W. Chen, Y. Chen, and K. Jia, "Deep Optimized Priors for 3D Shape Modeling and Reconstruction.", in IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2021.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Research Intern

Dexforce, Shenzhen

2021.11 - 2023.09

Research Intern

Shanghai AI Laboratory, Shanghai

2023.09 - 2024.01

SKILLS

Proficient: Python (Pytorch), Blender, LATEX

Familiar: C++, CUDA

AWARDS

Samsung Scholarship, South China University of Technology	2018.03
National Scholarship, South China University of Technology	2018.11
National Scholarship, South China University of Technology	2019.12